Guide to the Henry Raup Wagner Collection of Louisiana Manuscripts
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Henry Raup Wagner collection of Louisiana manuscripts
1792-1827
WA MSS S-343
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.5
(1 box)
Documents created in the Louisiana Province relating to debts and land grants or deeds, and government documents relating to boundaries and political relations with the United States, livestock regulations, and roads and bridges.
Wagner, Henry R. (Henry Raup), 1862-1957
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Henry Raup Wagner in 1919.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
Documents created in the Louisiana Province relating to debts and land grants or deeds, and government documents relating to boundaries and political relations with the United States, livestock regulations, and roads and bridges.
Deeds -- Louisiana; Land grants -- Louisiana; Louisiana -- History; Natchez (Miss.: District); New Orleans (La.); Proclamations -- Spain; Public officers -- Spain; Cox, Richard Smith, 1792-1865; Curtis, William, fl. 1793; Dunbar, William, 1749-1810; Gallagher, Jacinta; Gallaudet, Edgar; Lanclo, Antonio; Longuay, Francois de; Moore, Alexander; Pellerin, Bartholomé; Pellerin, Lubrey; Quitman, John Anthony, 1798-1858; Rivas, Francisco, fl. 1794; Deverget Sansovel, Francisco; La Chaise, Charles; Louisiana. Governor (1791-1797: Carondelet); Louisiana. Intendente
- Box and folder list, 1792 Jul 23
  - Dunbar, William. Expediente relative to the collection of a debt owed to the estate of E. Gallaudet by L. Pellerin. New Orleans., 1792 Jul 23 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Includes: Petition of Dunbar to Gov. Carondelet, the original note, Carondelet's orders, proceedings, and power of attorney from Dunbar to F. Deverget Sansovel.
  - Natchez (District, Province of Louisiana) Governor (Gayoso de Lemos). Land grant to William Curtis. Natchez., 1793 Jan 18 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Approved by Baron Carondelet, Governor of Louisiana.
  - Moore, Alexander. Petition for a land grant. Manshaque, La., 1794 Feb 25 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Endorsed by Francisco Rivas and approved by Baron Carondelet.
  - Gallagher, Jacinta. Petition for land grant. Natchez., 1794 Mar 17 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    With favorable endorsement by Baron Carondelet.
  - Natchez (District, Province of Louisiana) Governor (Gayoso de Lemos). Regulations governing livestock. Natchez., 1794 Sep 18 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    With this is sewn a decree of Oct 8, 1794 on repair of highways and bridges.
  - Natchez (District, Province of Louisiana) Governor (Gayoso de Lemos). Proclamation. Natchez., 1797 Mar 29 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Official seal affixed. Warns the inhabitants against political intrigue and assures them that the Spanish government will protect their rights.
  - Louisiana (Province) Governor. (Carondelet). Proclamation. New Orleans., 1797 May 24 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    With offical seal. States that delay in marking boundary with U.S. and reinforcement of Walnut Hill is due to British threat against Louisiana. Mutilated, affecting a few words.
  - Natchez (District, Province of Louisiana) Governor (Gayoso de Lemos). Proclamation. Natchez., 1797 Jun 14 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Denies rumors of war between Spain and the U.S., and forbids public meetings.
  - La Chaise, Charles. Copy of deed of sale to Francois de Longuay. New Orleans., 1798 Jan 20 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Louisiana (Province) Intendente. Expediente on the land claim of Antonio Lanclo. New Orleans., 1803 Jan 20 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Quitman, John Anthony. ALS to Richard S. Coxe. Natchez, Miss., 1827 Nov 4 (Box 1, Folder 11)